<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Break Even Brewing</title><link>https://breakevenbrewing.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Break Even Brewing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://breakevenbrewing.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bottling Beer</title><link>https://breakevenbrewing.github.io/articles/bottling-beer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breakevenbrewing.github.io/articles/bottling-beer/</guid><description>Bottling Beer Our process for bottle conditioning beer
Equipment Needed Beer Bottles and Caps(~12 per gallon) Bottle Caper Bottle Brush Bottling Bucket Tubing and Bottling Wand Bottle drying tower and sanitizing hand pump Star-San Priming sugar Transfer tubing from fermenter Hazards Identification and PPE / Safety Steps Required: PPE: Rubber boots
Hazardous Products: Star-San
Hazards: N/A
Preparation Taste the beer to be bottled. Confirm that Dialectal is not present.</description></item><item><title>SOP Template</title><link>https://breakevenbrewing.github.io/articles/sop-template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breakevenbrewing.github.io/articles/sop-template/</guid><description>Object and Scope Define the purpose of the SOP and what will be covered.
Equipment Needed A list of everything that will be needed to complete this SOP. More equipment More Hazards Identification and PPE / Safety Steps Required: PPE: Eye protection, rubber boots, respirator, gloves
Hazardous Products: chemicals, gasses, etc.
Hazards: Handling hazardous products (almost always), heat, working at height, LOTO, etc.
Preparation Copy the raw contents of this file.</description></item><item><title>Conical CIP</title><link>https://breakevenbrewing.github.io/articles/conical-cip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breakevenbrewing.github.io/articles/conical-cip/</guid><description>Cleaning Fermenters This will walk you through cleaning and sanitizing a fermenter so that it is ready for fresh wort to be transferred into it.
Equipment Needed CIP Pump CIP Spray Ball 1.5&amp;quot; TC Brewery hose to connect CIP Pump to CIP Spray Ball Alkaline Brewery Wash White wash basin 2&amp;quot; TC straight 8&amp;quot; run to return to basin Hazards Identification and PPE / Safety Steps Required: PPE: Eye protection, rubber boots, gloves</description></item></channel></rss>